<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>alumni on Bárbara Bitarello</title>
    <link>/categories/alumni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in alumni on Bárbara Bitarello</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/alumni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daphne Hansell</title>
      <link>/people/daphne/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/daphne/</guid>
      <description>Pronouns: she/her/hers
Fun Fact: I love to bake, listen to podcasts and feed stray cats.
In the Lab: Joined summer 2023 to work on an R package to calculate balancing selection. My interests are all things R! Also worked on developing an R package for the B215: Biostatistics with R course. Stayed until graduating (Spring 2024).
balselr - Balancing Selection Tests in R Broader project: Balancing selection: mechanisms, timescales, and signatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clementine Chen</title>
      <link>/people/clementine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/clementine/</guid>
      <description>Pronouns: she/her/hers
Hometown: Jinhua, China
Fun Fact: My favorite Disney characters are Alice and the Cheshire Cat.
In the lab: joined us for the summer research program 2022 and stayed until graduating (Spring 2024).
Update: starting a Masters program in Fall 2024 in Computational Biology and Quantitative Genetics @ Harvard T.H. Chan school of Public Health.
Quantifying the evidence for adaptive evolution of the TAS2R38 bitter receptor gene in primates Broader project: Evolution of bitter taste receptors in primates and other mammals/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gillyoung Koh</title>
      <link>/people/gillyoung/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/gillyoung/</guid>
      <description>Pronouns: she/her/hers
From Broomall, PA
Fun Fact: My favorite Disney character is Olaf because of how adorable and funny he is.
In the lab: joined us for the summer research program 2022 and stayed until graduating (Spring 2024).
Update: taking a year off before applying to medical schools.
Investigation of Long-Term Diversifying Evolution In TAS2R14, A Promiscuous Bitter Taste Receptor In Primates Broader project: Evolution of bitter taste receptors in primates and other mammals/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levi Raskin</title>
      <link>/people/levi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/levi/</guid>
      <description>Fun Fact: My favorite Disney-adjacent character is the Iron Giant.
From Oak Park, Illinois
In the lab: Joined us in Spring 2023, working on phylogenetic signal, phylogenetic methods, and hominin life history evolution. Co-mentured by Maja Šešelj.
Update: starting a PhD in Fall 2024 at UC Berkeley’s Integrative Biology program with (Dr. John Huelsenbeck)[https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/john-huelsenbeck].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyra Kovačić</title>
      <link>/people/kyra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/kyra/</guid>
      <description>In the lab: September 2021-May 2022 - the first of their kind!
Senior Thesis Project: &amp;ldquo;Investigating Signatures of Adaptive Evolution in Mammalian Bitter Taste Receptor Genes and Pseudogenes&amp;rdquo; Broader project: Evolution of bitter taste receptors in primates and other mammals/</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
